字幕：Hongjiang399  微信：Hongjiang399
Java编程语言随着很多年的发展，有着
The Java programming language has been developed over the years following some
十分严格的原则
very strict principles.
Java刚开始被创建时有5个原则，第一
The five principles of Java as declared when Java was created include, first,
Java是一门简单的、面向对象的并且容易熟悉的语言
that it's a simple, object- oriented, and familiar language.
它的简约性主要取决于其高度一致性
Its simplicity lies greatly in its consistency.
一旦你学会在Java中做某件事情，你将学会用同样的办法
Once you learn how to do one thing in Java, you know how to do it the same
利用整个语言做同样的事情，因其从来不会偏离
way throughout the language because it never deviates from the way the
其语言的基本结构
language is architected.
这是一门面向对象语言
It's an object-oriented language.
因此你一旦理解了封装、继承、和多态等原理
So once you understand the principles of encapsulation, inheritance, and
以及它们在Java编程语言中的实现方式
polymorphism and how those are implemented in the Java programming language,
你将会对如何构建你自己的程序有更深的感触
you'll have a much better sense of how to architect your applications.
对于那些应用C类型语言来工作的开发者们，例如C、C++等
And for developers who've worked with C-Style languages like C and C++, the
Java的语法是很熟悉的
syntax of Java is very familiar.
Java是一门坚固而安全的语言
Java was created to be robust and secure.
它的坚固性主要取决于其面向对象的特性，因为
Its robustness lies greatly in its object-oriented characteristics, because
你把所有东西都设计成了对象，每个东西都有其方法、函数
you're designing everything as an object, everything has methods or functions
及其性质(也即fields)
and properties also known as fields.
程序的创建是通过把多个类结合在一起而实现的
And you create applications by combining multiple classes together.
这让你能够把你的代码分成小块，并很容易进行调试和
This lets you create your code in small chunks and it makes it easy to debug and
长时间维护你的程序
maintain your applications over time.
Java是一门便携性的语言，因此你能够只编译一次
Java was designed to be portable, so that you'd be able to compile it once and
然后在多种操作系统和处理器上运行程序
then run your application on multiple operating systems and processors.
Java也是一门高性能的语言
Java was created to be high-performance.
最初版本的Java虚拟机并不如C++快
The original version of the Java Virtual Machine wasn't as fast as C++
但随着时间推移它有了很大的改进，现如今
applications, but over the years it's been improved enormously, and today
Java程序运行跟C++程序一样快甚至可以更快
Java applications run just as fast or sometimes even faster than applications built in C++.
最后，Java是一门解释型语言，它支持
And finally Java was created as an interpreted language, it supports
多线程并且具有动态性
multithreading and it's dynamic.
解释型语言表明其程序需先编译成一种格式文件
Interpreted, means that the application is compiled to a format that's
其可以在运行时被解释，而不是像机器码那样直接被运行
interpreted at runtime rather than being run as machine code directly, this is
这是Java具有便捷性的原因
what makes the applications portable.
Java是多线程的，它可以用来很容易地创建多任务程序
It's multithreaded, and it makes it easy to build applications that do more than
one thing at the same time.
Java是一门动态语言，意味着它的数据类型可以在运行时相互转换
And it's dynamic, in that it can change data types at runtime as long as those
只要这些数据类型是兼容的
data types are compatible with each other.
下面是Java的运行结构
Here is the runtime architecture of Java.
再一次，Java是解释型语言，即程序被编译成
Again, it's an interpreted language, the application is compiled to
字节码而非机器码，这是Java具有便捷性的原因
bytecode rather than machine language, and that's what makes it portable
可适用于不同操作系统
between operating systems.
这是当你运行程序时的整个软件状态
Here is the software stat that's used at runtime when you run your application.
从操作系统开始
You start with the operating system.
你可以在Windows、Mac、Linux、Solaris以及其他系统上运行Java程序
You can run Java applications on Windows, Mac, Linux, Solaris, and any other
只要系统上有可用的Java虚拟机
operating system for which there is a usable Java Virtual Machine.
大多数情况下你所用的Java虚拟机是源自
The Java Virtual Machine you use most of the time will be the one provided by
甲骨文的，其最初由Sun公司开发，但也有其他的Java虚拟机
Oracle, the one that was created by Sun Microsystems, but there are other JVMs
例如创建自IBM的、由谷歌所提供的安卓虚拟机
out there provided by IBM, the Virtual Machine that's provided for Android by
还有一些其他虚拟机
Google and many others.
虚拟机上有核心运行时库以及一些额外的库
On top of the Virtual Machine you add the core runtime and additional libraries.
核心运行时库有时也被称为Java类库，包含了
The core runtime is sometimes called the Java Class Library, and it consists of
所有由Java开发工具所提供的功能函数
all of the functionality that's provided with the core Java developer toolkit.
最后，你的程序是作为编译过的字节码在最上层运行的
And finally your application runs on top of all that once again as compiled bytecode.
让我们比较一下Java和其他一些语言
So let's compare Java to a couple of popular languages.
首先是C++，Java最初是由C++开发者创建的，他们想着
First C++, Java was originally created by C++ developers and they had in mind
要改善开发者的机遇
improving the developers' lot.
下面是Java和C++的一些不同点
Here are some ways in which Java is different from C++.
如果你是一个C开发者，那么你的代码也可在C++中运行
If you're a C developer all of your code can be run in C++ as well.
这两门语言是相互兼容的，但Java就不是这样的
The two languages are compatible with each other, that's not true for Java.
尽管Java在语法上很接近C和C++，但其代码具有独立性
Even though Java has syntax that's very similar to C and C++, its code is unique.
它有着独立的规则和独立的语法
It has its own rules and its own syntax.
我之前提到C++是直接编译成机器码来运行
I have mentioned earlier that C++ is compiled to native machine language and
从而运行非常快速，并可以调用底层函数，
while that makes it very fast and gives it access to low-level functions, it
这意味着你需要针对不同操作系统和处理器进行重新编译
means that your application has to be recompiled for each operating system and
从而在特定环境中运行
processor that you want to target.
Java是被编译成字节码的
Java is compiled to bytecode.
因C++直接编译成机器码的，所以它允许你直接调用
Because C++ is compiled to native machine language, it allows direct calls
本地系统的功能
to the native system.
Java中有一个接口叫做Java本地接口，简称JNI
In Java there is an interface called Java Native Interface sometimes called JNI,
其让你能通过Java虚拟机调用本地系统的功能
that lets you call those native functions through the JVM.
C++让你可以只写一次代码，只要你遵循标准C++语法，然后你
C++ lets you write once and then as long as you followed standard C++ syntax you
可以在各个操作系统中进行重新编译，相比之下
can recompile for each operating system you are targeting, whereas the
Java的原则是“一次编写，随处运行”
principles of Java say that you can write once and run anywhere.
Java运行于一个受保护的虚拟机环境，再一次，你需要
Java runs in a protected virtual machine environment, and again, you have to go
通过JNI接口来实现对底层系统功能的调用
through that JNI interface to make those low-level system function calls.
下面是另一个这两门语言十分明显的不同点
Here's a way in which the two languages are very different.
C++需要详尽的内存管理以及运用指针
C++ requires explicit memory management and uses pointers.
因此C++程序可能具有内存泄漏，除非开发者
C++ applications as a result can have memory leaks and it's up to the developer
确保在程序中闭合了所有的漏洞
to make sure that they've sealed up all the holes in their application.
而Java语言会为你自动管理内存
In Java, memory is managed for you.
每当你创建了一个类/对象的实例，Java虚拟机
When you create instances of classes or objects, the Java Virtual Machine
会自动分配内存
automatically allocates the memory.
当你用完这个对象，Java虚拟机会打扫内存并销毁
And when you're done with the objects the JVM sweeps up the memory by destroying
没被引用的对象，这个功能叫垃圾回收器
dereferenced objects, this is called the Garbage Collector.
这意味着在Java程序中你不需要知道具体有多少
This means that in Java applications you don't have to know specifically how
内存被消耗，但你还是需要注意
much memory is being used at any given time, you still have to pay attention to
确保你只创建了所必需的对象
making sure that you only create the objects you need.
在C++中你可以运用多重继承，也就是当你定义
And in C++ you can use multiple inheritance, this means that when you define an
一个对象时你可以使之从多个父类继承而来
object you can inherit functionality for multiple super classes.
而Java采用的是单继承模型，因此你只能继承自唯一
The Java inheritance model is single inheritance so you can only inherit
一个直接的父类
directly from a single superclass.
这使得你更容易找到问题，特别是
This makes it easier to figure out where there are problems when your
你的程序有错误的时候
application has bugs.
让我们比较一下Java和JavaScript
Let's also compare Java to JavaScript.
虽然这两门语言都有名词“Java”，但它们其实
Even though the names of these languages share the term Java, they are really
并没什么关系
not closely related.
Java不兼容前面的两门语言，即使它
Java again wasn't compatible with previous languages even though it
借鉴了C的语法
borrowed syntax from C.
JavaScript有一个基本标准叫ECMAScript
JavaScript has morphed into a standard known as ECMAScript or ECMAScript.
其他同样基于ECMAScript标准的包括Adobe的
Other languages that are based on the ECMAScript standard include Adobe's
ActionScript 3.0和微软的JScript，还有其他一些
ActionScript 3.0 and JScript from Microsoft and a number of others.
Java先被编译成字节码然后在运行时被解释
Java is compiled to bytecode and interpreted at runtime.
而JavaScript是直接从源代码解释而来的
JavaScript is interpreted directly from source code.
Java可以通过JNI接口调用底层功能，而
Java can make native function calls through the JNI interface, while in
JavaScript只要是运行在浏览器上，它就必须被一个
JavaScript at least as it's implemented in a browser, is restricted to something
浏览器沙盒所限制
called a browser Sandbox.
它只能运行在一个沙盒中，且不能调用本地底层功能
It can only play in the Sandbox, and it can't make native function calls.
Java是一次编写，随处运行
Java is write once, run anywhere.
而JavaScript更为便捷，因其兼容
JavaScript is even more portable in the sense that it has brought compatibility
多种浏览器和操作系统
in many browsers and many operating systems.
Java运行于一个受保护的虚拟机，但你必须确保
Java runs in a protected virtual machine but you have to explicitly have that
虚拟机已经被安装
virtual machine installed.
类似地，JavaScript运行于浏览器中，受限于
And in a similar fashion JavaScript is executed by the browser and restricted to
特定的浏览器沙盒，出于安全考虑
that browser sandbox for security.
两门语言均自动为你管理内存，均不需要你
Both languages manage the memory for you, neither requires that you specifically
对内存分配和打扫
allocate or deallocate memory.
从继承角度看，Java使用了传统的类的继承
And in terms of inheritance, Java uses a traditional class-based inheritance
也即你定义类，然后继承其功能
where you define classes and then inherit their functionality.
JavaScript使用一种叫原型继承
JavaScript uses something called prototype-based inheritance.
这种继承允许你在运行时增加函数、属性、以及一些其他功能到
This model allows you to add functions, properties, and other functionality to a
定义过的类中，这是Java所不允许的
pre-defined class at runtime, something Java doesn't allow you to do.
综上，这就是Java的一些规则，以及跟
So that's a look at the principles of Java and how you might compare this
C++和JavaScript的一些对比
language to C++ and JavaScript.
从排序来说，你可以认为C++是最为严格的，Java
In the continuum of languages you might play C++ at the strictest level, Java
位于中间，而JavaScript是最具动态性的。
somewhere in the middle, and JavaScript at the most dynamic.
你可以使用Java，尤其是搭建只有它才最适合的应用的时候
And you typically use Java when you want to build applications that rely on that language.
字幕GitHub: https://github.com/Hongjiang399/JavaEssentialTrainingSRT.git